Prepare to be entertained.
Gladiator II is a action, adventure, drama film directed by Ridley Scott.
Years after witnessing the death of the revered hero Maximus at the hands of his uncle, Lucius is forced to enter the
Colosseum after his home is conquered by the tyrannical Emperors who now lead Rome with an iron fist.
With rage in his heart and the future of the Empire at stake, Lucius must look to his
past to find strength and honor to return the glory of Rome to its people.
Lucius, played by Paul Mescal.
Macrinus, played by Denzel Washington.
General Acacius, played by Pedro Pascal.
Lucilla, played by Connie Nielsen.
Emperor Geta, played by Joseph Quinn.
Emperor Caracalla, played by Fred Hechinger.
Gladiator II is a 2024 epic historical film
directed and produced by Ridley Scott.
The sequel to Gladiator (2000), it was written by David Scarpa
based on a story he wrote with Peter Craig.
The film was produced by Scott Free Productions and
distributed by Paramount Pictures.
It stars Paul Mescal, Pedro Pascal, Joseph Quinn, Fred
Hechinger, Connie Nielsen, and Denzel Washington.
Derek Jacobi and Nielsen reprise their roles from the first
film, with Mescal replacing Spencer Treat Clark.
Mescal portrays Lucius Verus Aurelius, the exiled Prince of Rome, who becomes a prisoner of war and fights as a
gladiator for Macrinus, a former slave who plots to overthrow the twin emperors Caracalla and Geta.
A sequel to Gladiator was discussed as early as June 2001, with David
Franzoni and John Logan set to return as screenwriters.
Over the next few years, Scott offered occasional updates, including the possible involvement of the original film's lead
actor, Russell Crowe, along with plot ideas about the Roman afterlife and different historical time periods.
Development was halted when DreamWorks Pictures was sold to Paramount in 2006.
The film was finally announced in 2018, and Mescal was cast in the lead
role in January 2023, with a script by David Scarpa.
Filming took place between June 2023 and January 2024, with a
five-month delay due to the 2023 Hollywood labor disputes.
Gladiator II premiered in Sydney, Australia, on October 30, 2024, and was released in the
United Kingdom on November 15 and in the United States on November 22.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics, although it was considered
inferior to its predecessor, and grossed $462.2 million worldwide.
It received two nominations at the 82nd Golden Globe Awards: Cinematic and Box Office Achievement and Best
Supporting Actor for Washington, and was nominated for Best Costume Design at the 97th Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of gladiator, roman empire,
ancient rome, sequel, 3rd century.
The tone is emotional.